### SABASTIAN HIGHTON

## thehighton.com

(470) 505-8286 | sthighton@gmail.com

#### SUMMARY

Recent graduate in computer science seeking software development role to gain high quality experience. Over two years of software development and data science in a university environment. Self-starter applying software development and machine learning models to real-world problems. Graduated summa cum laude a year and a half early as a co-author of conference accepted research.

### **EDUCATION**

University of North Georgia, Mike Cottrell College of Business

Dahlonega, GA

**BS** Computer Science

GPA: 3.92/4.0

December 2023

Summa Cum Laude

#### **EXPERIENCE**

University of North Georgia

Dahlonega, GA

### **National Science Foundation Funded Research Assistant**

May 2023 - Aug 2023

- Conducted research with Linux virtual machines, python code, and supercomputers in San Diego and Pittsburgh on live hyperspectral image segmentation
- Worked with multiple machine learning models while clearly documenting all findings
- Coordinated and communicated effectively with a coresearcher and multiple professors
- Communicated quality updates for meetings three times weekly until position closed

University of North Georgia

Dahlonega, GA

# **Co-Author of Research**

September 2022 – December 2023

- Conducted research to predict the likelihood of a microRNA strand binding to a target mRNA strand using machine learning algorithms such as a convolutional neural network
- Contributed to and reviewed IEEE conference accepted research

Chick-Fil-A

Dawsonville, GA

**Team Member** 

June 2021 – August 2021

- Completed orders quickly and accurately while keeping in constant communication with the team
- Maintained an orderly and clean work environment under intense pressure
- Maintained flexibility to ensure critical business needs were met
- Left to pursue bachelor degree in computer science full-time

### **SKILLS**

Python, Web Development, Data Science, Research, Linux, Jupyter, Supercomputers